翻译 灰灰是菇凉
翻译 胡说大王
翻译 潇然
翻译 showeryhe
翻译 桃小兔吃冰棒
翻译 SophiaSaaag
翻译 小泡椒
时间轴 倩倩
时间轴 Poxle
时间轴 想念Gallifrey的Wholock
校对 灰灰是菇凉
后期&总监 灰灰是菇凉
西部世界
第一季  第七集
爸爸
Dad.
醒醒
Wake up.
快醒醒
我睡着了
I must've drifted off.
刚才讲到哪儿了
Where were we?
那个疯子
The madman.
对
Of course.
疯帽子
The Hatter...
他说
who says,
"如果我有个属于自己的世界
"If I had a world of my own,
那里将会是一片混沌
everything would be nonsense.
万物皆失去其本真
Nothing would be what it is
所有东西都会变了样子"
because everything would be what it isn't."
所有东西都会变了样子
Everything would be what it isn't?
我也是
Even me.
你很棒
You're perfect.
你一定会战胜病魔的
You're gonna beat this.
我保证
I promise you.
来  我们来讲点有趣的
Now, let's skip to something fun.
爸爸
Dad.
-怎么了  查理  -听我说
- What is it, Charlie? - Listen to me.
听着
Listen.
查理
Charlie?
Charlie!
最后一个问题  你是否质疑过你眼中现实世界的本质
And finally, have you ever questioned the nature of your reality?
没有
No.
很好
Good.
我发现你在故事线中
Now, then, I see you had
与一位客人进行了
a blacklisted exchange with a guest
一次禁止发生的交流
in the course of your narrative.
说说怎么回事
Can you tell me what happened?
他说想从我身上剁一块下来
He said he wanted to cut off a piece of me
带回家去
to take home in his carry-on,
说要挂在引擎盖上
that he wanted to mount it on the hood of his car
给他朋友看
for his friends to see.
我告诉他如果想要纪念品
I told him if he wanted a trophy,
我可以把他剁了
I could cut pieces of him off
让他去奥尔维多找肉片
and let him fish for them in the Olvido.
这次交流
And did this exchange
是否让你对你的世界产生了质疑
make you question anything about your world?
没有
No.
这个世界还是一样的完蛋
This world is as doomed as ever.
只是为了让我安心点，请问...
And just for my peace of mind...
自我意识测试
赫克托·艾斯卡顿
准备
你对这些图片有印象吗
Anything about these images that jumps out to you?
我看不出来什么
They don't look like anything to me.
手头积压的活已经处理完15%了
We're through 15% of the backlog.
照这个速度来看  下班前能赶上进度
As it stands, we should be caught up by end of day.
-很好  -还有  先生  等您这边处理完
- Good. - And, uh, when you're done here, sir,
管理部门要求他立刻过去
there's a priority request for him from Management.
你看到埃尔希吗
Have you seen Elsie?
她本该来帮我做事的
She was supposed to give me a hand on something.
没有  系统显示
No. Uh, according to the system,
她今天开始休假
she started her leave today.
有什么我能帮您的吗
Is there something I could help you with?
不了  谢谢
No, thanks.
加注
Raise.
跟了
I'll call.
这种烂牌你也跟
You're calling with that shit?
德洛丽丝  你也来玩一把
Dolores, why don't you play a hand?
你这是白费口舌
You're wasting your breath.
小姑娘心里对我有怨
Girl's harboring a grudge.
这也不能怪你  甜心
I don't blame you, sweetheart.
我的确对你俩干了些坏事
I did some ugly things to you both.
不过这不是私人恩怨
But it wasn't personal.
南方军和政府称之为战争
Confederados and the government like to call this thing a war,
但是他们的对手是拿石头当武器的
but they're fighting starving farmers
饥饿的农民
armed with rocks.
这根本不是什么战争
That ain't no war.
这是屠杀
It's a slaughter.
再来一次的话
If I had to do it all again,
我还是会对你们痛下狠手
I'd fuck you both over just as hard.
好吧  我们知道你的立场了
Well, I guess we know where you stand.
别装得自己有多无辜的样子
Don't pretend like you're so innocent.
我可记得  你们来找我
Way I recollect, y'all came to me,
是想加入那些人渣跟他们去打仗
looking to join up with those crooked assholes and their war effort.
那不是我们的主意
Not our idea.
是我朋友想...
My friend wanted--
我猜他想看看最后会怎么样
I guess he wanted to see what was at the end of all this.
结果呢  看吧
And yet, here you are.
你的朋友没能撑到这里
Your friend didn't make it this far.
也许你的欲望比自己想象中的更多
Maybe you've got more of an appetite for this than you think.
威廉
William.
那是什么
What is it?
我们已经到了幽灵之国
We're in Ghost Nation territory.
这里到处都是野蛮人的部落
Most savage tribe there is.
那是些不请自来的人的头骨
Those are the folks who came calling without an invitation.
你是说就像我们现在一样不请自来吗
You mean exactly what we're doing right now?
坐火车是唯一的方式
The train's the only way through.
走路的话  不到一个小时我们都会死
On foot we'll be dead in under an hour.
一旦经过了他们的领地  就能停车了
As soon as we're clear of their territory, we can stop.
你们可以跟我一起走  这里只有杀戮
You can come with me. Nothing here on out but slaughter.
正在呼叫
埃尔希·休斯
呼叫失败
您所拨打的号码暂时无法接通
The user you are trying to access cannot be located.
如需转录信息  请说"信息"
Say "Message" to transcribe a message.
位置
报告
编辑
搜索
无法定位
你找我吗  没什么事吧
You wanted to see me? Is everything okay?
昨晚你走得很急
You left rather abruptly last night.
你是有事想跟我说吗
Was there something you wanted to tell me?
没有
No, I don't think so.
黑尔正在检查所有部门
Hale is looking over every department
你们部门诊断进度落后了
and yours is running behind on diagnostics.
毕竟董事会在这
It would be best if we presented
至少表面上我们要表现得专业点
at least a semblance of professionalism while the board is here.
没事的
We'll be fine.
我的手下知道该怎么做
My people know how to do their jobs.
如果他们能拿出质疑我团队调查的
If they applied half as much energy to their work
一半的精力来投入工作...
as they have to second-guessing my team's investigation--
都过去了
That's all over.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
确定
Yes.
很好
Good.
你还好吧
You doing okay?
很好  谢谢
I'm fine. Thank you.
抱歉  我以为你说要见我
I'm sorry. I thought you requested a meeting.
-我搞错了  -我是要见你
- My mistake. - I did.
请进
Come in.
快回来
Get back here.
带上你的朋友
Bring your friend.
那你呢  怎样的命运转折...
What about you? What turns of fate--
如果现在不方便  我可以一会再来
I could come back later if this isn't a good time.
不会很久
This won't take long.
特蕾莎  你的工作一直做得很好
Theresa, you've always been good at your job
目前为止  董事会很满意你的表现
and the board has been impressed with your performance so far,
所以我们很惊讶居然出现了伐木工这个乱子
which is why we were so surprised by this woodcutter mess.
只是个小挫折
A small setback.
他滑了一跤  拿石头猛砸自己的脑袋
He slipped on a fucking rock and bashed his own head in
还骑到了一个行为技术人员身上
while basically on top of a behavior tech.
还有  福特突然要用园区大半资源
Meanwhile, Ford is suddenly using half the park's resources
来建造什么新故事线
to build some new narrative?
能借支烟吗
Can I bum a cigarette?
天呐  我知道你为什么又开始抽烟了
God, I see why you took these up again.
我提醒你一下
Let me remind you of something.
这个地方  这里的员工都不算什么
This place, the people who work here are nothing.
我们对这个地方
Our interest in this place
唯一的兴趣就是知识产权
is entirely in the intellectual property.
就是代码
The code.
接待员的思想  故事线
The hosts' minds, the storylines--
我一点也不在乎什么接待员
I don't give a rat's ass about the hosts.
提洛公司在乎的是研究项目
It's our little research project that Delos cares about.
这才是真正有价值的
That's where the real value is.
由于我的某个前任
And due to a lack of foresight
缺乏远见
on part of one of my predecessors,
35年来的资料
35 years of information--
原始资料  都在这里
raw information-- exists here.
别的地方都没有
Nowhere else.
福特这点做得滴水不漏
Ford has always ensured that.
你是个聪明的女人
Now, you are a smart enough woman.
你说说看  为什么我们要你来确保这些
Tell me, why would we need you to secure all of it?
因为你要开除他
Because you're going to fire him.
你不能开除一个创造了帝国的人
You don't fire someone who created an empire.
你得礼貌地请他退休
You ask him to retire politely.
如果这个人有动动手指
And if that person has the ability to snap his fingers
就能抹去整个帝国价值的能力
and erase the value of that empire,
你得确保你有应急措施
you have to make sure you have a contingency.
所以  我们俩
So, you and I need to ensure
得在其他董事抵达之前完成此事
that by the time the rest of the board arrives,
我们正处于过渡期
we are on course for that transition.
懂吗
Okay?
我喜欢你
I like you.
不是喜欢你这个人  而是喜欢你做这个工作
Well, not personally, but I like you for this job,
所以我会再给你一次机会
which is why I'm gonna give you another chance
处理好这个操蛋的情况
to get a handle on this particular bitch of a situation.
但对诸神来说
But the gods...
他们需要一场血祭
they require a blood sacrifice.
我们得展示出
We need to demonstrate just how dangerous
福特的创造会有多危险
Ford's creations can be.
不
No.
不能这么明显
No, nothing so obvious.
我们需要一个完全意想不到的人
We need someone thoroughly unexpected.
我跟你说过  别把嘴张那么大
I told you never open your mouth that wide
除非有人给钱要干你的嘴
unless someone's paying you for it.
抱歉  梅芙
Sorry, Maeve.
我昨晚没怎么睡觉
I didn't sleep much last night.
你做什么噩梦了
What are these nightmares you have about?
你梦到过你变成另一个人吗
Do you ever dream you're someone else?
没有吧
I don't think so.
为什么这么问
Why?
你有没有想过这到底是不是自己想要的人生
You ever thought about whether this is really the life you want?
我没想过一辈子干这行
I don't intend to make this my life's work.
无意冒犯
No offense.
我家里有个农场
My family's got a farm.
土地贫瘠  寸草不生
Bad soil. Nothing grows.
我会寄钱回去
I send money back to them.
他们以为我在服装店工作
They think I work in a dress shop.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我只是按你的吩咐做
I'm just doing what you told me to.
再做几年这个
A couple more years of this and...
我就可以去过我想要的人生了
then I can have whatever life I want.
我要把家人带出那片荒漠
I'm gonna get my family out of the desert.
搬去某个
We're gonna go somewhere...
冷的地方
cold.
有朝一日吧
Someday.
哪个
Which one is it?
吧台旁的那个  上
It's the one at the bar. Go.
快点  在游客上来前搞定
Quick, before the guests upstairs finish up.
她肯定犯了什么严重的事
Whatever she did, it must've been serious
才让我们大白天的来抓她
if they're making us grab her in broad daylight.
人到手  走吧
We got her. Let's go.
你应该歇歇
You're supposed to be resting.
我们坐着一列装满炸药的火车
We're riding a train full
行驶在一片荒蛮之地上
with explosives through scalping territory.
我可睡不着
Not sleepy.
能问你点事吗
Can I ask you something?
关于你在寻找的那个地方
This place you're looking for,
你为什么那么确信它存在
what makes you so sure it exists?
我不确信
I'm not.
以前  我对这个世界很确信
My life before, I was so sure of the world.
但现在感觉这只是个谎言
But now it feels like a lie.
我只知道无论前方是什么  我都永不回头
Only thing I know is whatever's out there, I'm never going back.
你在找什么
What is it you're looking for?
劳伦斯说得对
Lawrence is right.
你本可以留在珀里亚或是回去
You could've stayed in Pariah or gone back,
但你却在这里
but you're here.
和我一起
With me.
小时候只有书陪着我
The only thing I had when I was a kid were books.
我活在书的世界里
I used to live in them.
我曾经睡着后
I used to go to sleep
梦见我在其中一本书中醒来
dreaming I'd wake up inside one of them
因为书有意义
'cause they had meaning.
这里  就像我在其中一篇故事中醒来
This place, this is like I woke up inside one of those stories.
也许我只是想找出其意义吧
I guess I just wanna find out what it means.
我不想活在故事里
I don't wanna be in a story.
我想要的不是展望未来或是回顾过去
All I want is to not look forward or back.
我只想
I just wanna be...
活在当下
in the moment I'm in.
德洛丽丝
Dolores,
在家里  有个女人  朱丽叶
back home, there's a woman, Juliet,
我工作的那个公司是她爸爸的
and her father owns the company where I work.
她是  罗根的妹妹
She's, uh, Logan's sister.
是的
Yeah.
等我回家  就要和她结婚了
And when I get home, we're getting married.
你要找的那个地方  我会帮你找到
The place you're after, I will help you find it.
但我不能留下
But I can't stay.
外面有生活在等着我
I have a life waiting for me.
对不起
I'm sorry.
没关系
Of course.
德洛丽丝
Dolores.
我这辈子都在伪装自己
I've been pretending my whole life.
假装自己毫不在意  假装自己有所归属
Pretending I don't mind, pretending I belong.
我的人生就建立在谎言之上
My life's built on it.
那是个很好的人生  是我一直渴望的人生
And it's a good life. It's a life I've always wanted.
但来到这里之后
But then I came here
我突然窥见了
and I get a glimpse for a second
一个我不用伪装自己的人生
of a life in which I don't have to pretend.
我可以真正活着的人生
A life in which I can be truly alive.
知道了这种人生是什么感觉
How can I go back to pretending
我还怎么回去继续伪装自己
when I know what this feels like?
黑尔女士
Miss Hale.
我不知道以你的洞察力
I was not aware those with your level of insight
还需要用到镜子
needed any more reflection.
福特博士  还是这么有魅力
Dr. Ford. Always charming.
什么情况
What is this?
显然  卡伦女士和希尔女士
Apparently, Miss Cullen and Miss Hale
要给我们做个展示
have a presentation for us.
关于什么
What about?
鉴于最近接待员故障的报告
Following the recent reports of host malfunction,
我们请质保部门检查了上次失败的更新
we asked QA to check the last abortive update,
就是加入"冥思"的那个
which featured the reveries,
应该是叫这个名字
as I believe they're called.
很抱歉地告诉你卡伦女士及其团队
I'm sorry to report that Miss Cullen and her team
发现了一些令人担忧的东西
uncovered some worrisome findings.
在审查代码时
In the course of our code review,
我们发现了一些令人不安的东西
we found something quite disturbing.
把她唤醒
Wake her up.
我们将克莱门汀·彭尼法瑟设回上一版本的更新
We set Clementine Pennyfeather back to her previous update.
我们当时发现该版本
When we discovered the build was buggy
因为最后注入的冥思代码而出了问题
due to a last-minute injection of the reverie code,
于是立刻将所有被感染的接待员回滚至先前的版本
we quickly rolled all the infected hosts back to their prior builds.
你是新来的
Mm, you're new.
细皮嫩肉的
Not much of a rind on you.
不
No!
不要  不
No! No!
No, no.
别打了  不要
No, no, no...
求求你  求求你
Please. Please.
救救我
Help me!
求求你们  求求你们
Please, please, please!
-不要  -好了  够了
- No! - All right, that's enough.
停
Freeze.
相信你们都看出来了
As you've no doubt gathered,
这位技术人员也是一位接待员
our tech is, in fact, a host.
为了这次模拟
One that has been coded for the purposes
照人类行为来编码
of this simulation to read as a human.
如你们所见  行为保护程序
And as you can see, behavioral safeguards
按预期正常运行
are operating exactly as you would expect.
将她重设  抹去记忆
Reset her. Wipe her memory.
好的  咱们再来一次
Okay, let's do this again.
你是新来的
You're new.
细皮嫩肉的
Not much of a rind on you.
够了  亲爱的
That's enough, sweetheart.
够了
That's enough.
停止所有运动功能
Freeze all motor functions.
我们检查的每一例
In each case we examined,
出故障的接待员都有重设不当
the malfunctioning hosts were not resetting properly.
未被抹去的数据存储
The retention of data that hadn't been wiped
使决策装置过载
overloaded their decision-making apparatus,
最终导致系统故障
eventually causing a system failure
以致忽略其首要规则
that allowed for override of their primary rule set.
冥思的问题在于
The concern with the reveries
接待员会记得一些事  并就其
is that the hosts will remember some of their experiences
采取行动
and act on them.
你是说这些接待员
You're telling us that these hosts
会响应怨恨情绪吗
were responding to a grudge?
我正是这个意思  罗威先生
That's exactly what I'm saying, Mr. Lowe.
你居然用"怨恨"这个词  有趣
And funny you should use that particular word, "Grudge,"
因为最近最令我困扰的是
since what was most troubling to me
行为部门好几位技术人员
was that several techs in behavior
对他们部门的头儿
voiced these exact same concerns
也有着同样的担忧
to the head of their department.
你未经彻底审查  且对可能后果
You put this code out without proper vetting
缺乏合理预判的情况下  就将这段代码投入使用
and without reasonable understanding of its ramifications.
这样看来  要么这代码不是你写的
So, either you didn't write it
要么你就已经草率到
or you're getting sloppy
不计客人生命安危的地步
to the point of risking the lives of our guests.
我也是见过世面的人  罗威先生
Few things surprise me anymore, Mr. Lowe,
但疏忽至此还是叫我震惊得说不出话
but this level of negligence is fucking breathtaking.
这已经不是回滚就能解决的范畴了
We are way beyond rollback territory.
在接下来的六个月
Within the next six months,
我们必须从零开始
we'll need to rebuild the hosts
重建这些接待员
from the ground up.
你的意思是要我们给他们做额叶切除
You want us to lobotomize them is what you're saying.
不  没有你  罗威先生
No, not you, Mr. Lowe.
毕竟  这是你的责任
After all, this was your responsibility,
如果你对自己的过失
assuming that you have nothing to share with us
没有其他解释的话
in terms of your culpability.
没有
No.
那么你被解雇了
Then you're fired.
早安  威廉
Morning, William.
我没想吵醒你
I-- I didn't wanna wake you.
我知道
I know...
昨晚真是没想到
last night was unexpected.
如果你后悔了
If you regret it...
我决不后悔
I don't regret a thing.
我知道你家中还有人在等你
I know you have someone waiting for you at home.
如今那感觉好不真实
All that feels so unreal now.
我以前还认为这地方只是
I used to think this place was all about...
迎合原始本能
pandering to your baser instincts.
现在我明白了
Now I understand.
它并不是要满足你最低俗的人性
It doesn't cater to your lowest self,
而是要揭露你最深层的自我
it reveals your deepest self.
它让我们看清自己
It shows you who you really are.
还记得我们抛下罗根时他的表情吗
You remember the look on Logan's face when we left him behind?
你知道我很久前就想这么做
Do you know how long I've wanted to do that,
想让他知道我对他的看法吗
to let him know what I think of him?
而你  昨晚
And you, last night,
我从没有过那种感觉
I've never felt that way before,
对任何一个女人都没有
not with any woman.
你打开了我潜藏的内心世界
You've unlocked something in me.
我并非一把钥匙  威廉
I'm not a key, William.
我只是我
I'm just me.
那是什么
What is that?
我不知道
I don't know.
在家的时候  我常作画
At home, I used to paint.
大多是风景  但是我总是在
Landscapes mostly, but I was always just...
临摹我身外的世界
copying the world outside me.
今早我醒来就想到
This morning, I woke up and I thought...
如果我画些新的东西会是什么样
"What if I drew something new?"
我想象了一些美丽的场景
I imagined something beautiful.
一个依山傍海的地方
A place where the mountains meet the sea.
到这里来的每个人
Everyone who comes here
都渴望寻求战争或刺激
is longing for excitement or conflict,
而你渴望的
and you're just...
却是截然相反的东西
dreaming of the opposite.
那你呢  威廉
Well, what about you, William?
你渴望什么
What do you dream of?
怎么了
What is it?
-我们被埋伏了  -是幽灵之国的人吗
- Ambush. - Is it the Ghost Nation?
更糟  是南方军
Worse. The Confederados.
真他妈的懦夫
Fucking coward.
与上帝同在  混账东西
Vaya con dios, motherfuckers.
他们要逃  快  兄弟  起来
They're making a run for it! Come on, boys, get up!
快  靠近点
Come on, stay close!
上  兄弟们
Go, boys!
德洛丽丝
Dolores!
追  追  把他们拿下
Go, go! Take 'em down!
追  追
Go, go!
幽灵之国
Ghost Nation!
我们走
Let's go!
停下  威廉  停下
Stop, William! Stop!
这是真的
It's real...
我梦到的地方
what I dreamt.
这是你画的那个地方
It's the place you drew.
你走吗
You coming?
幽灵们一旦
Once the Ghosts is done
跟那些可怜的混蛋们熟悉完之后
acquainting themselves with those poor bastards,
就会来追我们了
they'll be coming after us.
我的这几个战友求战心切
My friends here are itching to join the war effort.
我觉得我已经受够战争了
Think I've had enough of war.
你呢
How about you?
你可是个杀人高手
You got a knack for killing.
恐怕我们要在这里分道扬镳了
I'm afraid this is where we part ways.
当心点
Careful.
你们向西走渡过那条河
If you're heading west across that river,
也许就能逃离战场了
you may be leaving the fighting behind,
但是你们会进入一片未知的领土
but you're gonna be in unclaimed territories.
那里是什么地方
What's out that way?
那你只能问天问大地了
You're gonna have to ask the dust.
从没有东西从那回来过
Ain't nothing ever come back from there.
差不多快完成了
We're almost done here.
我来收尾吧
Why don't I close up?
你才在上面呆了不到24个小时
You've been topside for less than 24 hours.
你到下面来得这么勤  会引起怀疑的
You keep coming down this often, people are going to notice.
-克莱在哪  -我不知道
- Where's Clem? - I don't know.
我没看到她  怎么了
I haven't seen her. Why?
找到她  马上
Find her. Now.
怎么了
What?
她在哪
Where is she?
我不知道
I don't know.
克莱门汀·彭尼法瑟
位置  人体车间
她在这  我们走
She's here. Let's go.
我们不能去那  上层领导在那里
We can't. The brass will be there.
你可别糊弄我  菲利克斯
You don't want to fuck with me, Felix.
马上带我去那
Take me there now.
走慢点
Slow down.
请把头往后仰  克莱
Tilt your head back, please, Clem.
-有问题吗  -没有
- Is there a problem? - No.
抱歉
Sorry.
特蕾莎
Theresa.
能借一步说话吗
May I have a word?
当然
Sure.
我很钦佩你的专业精神
I appreciate your professionalism,
但其实你真的不用这么费心
but you really don't need to bother with this,
毕竟你现在已经不是这里的雇员了
given the change in your employment status.
那个测试是个骗局
The test was a sham.
那是你和黑尔一起搞的小表演吗
The little show you and Hale put on?
从技术层面来说完全是漏洞百出
Completely transparent from a technical perspective,
这计策拙劣的我都为你感到羞愧
clumsy to the point of making me embarrassed for you.
-羞愧  -连我都能一眼看穿
- Embarrassed? - If I saw through it,
福特会怎么看可想而知
I can only imagine what Ford was thinking.
这段代码有很明显的
There were glaringly obvious markers
人为干预痕迹
of human intervention in the code.
如果你的程序员真有那么棒
If your programmers were any good,
他们早就会来我这工作了
they'd be working for me.
而且我知道你还有你的手下和那个失散的机器人
And I know you and your team were responsible for the stray
以及卫星传输脱不了干系
and its satellite transmission.
-伯尼  -我不管你什么说辞
- Bernie-- - I don't care.
40年前
40 years ago,
这里建立时的代码有一半都是福特的搭档写的
Ford's partner wrote half the code this place was founded on.
你在实验室里说的话没错
What you said in the lab was right.
我们不知道接待员是怎样运作的
We don't know how the hosts work,
我也觉得他们有些问题
and I think there's something wrong with them.
福特对此的解释更加证实了我的直觉
Ford's explanation only bolsters my hunch.
偏离程序行为的能力
The ability to deviate from program behavior
是由对旧角色的记忆产生的
arises out of the host's recall of past iterations.
你觉得是有关联的  记忆和...
You're thinking there's a connection between memory and--
和即兴反应  没错
And improvisation, yes.
重复导致变异
Out of repetition comes variation.
无数次的重复过后
And after countless cycles of repetition,
接待员们开始变异
these hosts, they were varying.
他们即将经历某种转变
They were on the verge of some kind of change.
你得知道  一直以来我都是
You have to know my chief concern
在为乐园以及游客着想
has always been the well-being of this park and the people in it.
我知道
I know.
所以我要给你看点东西
Which is why I need to show you something.
-跟她说说话  -你先
- Talk to her. - You first.
我不想把她撤掉
Look, I didn't want to retire her.
我知道你把她当做朋友
I know she's, like, your friend,
或者是...
or-- I guess.
但...如果我不这么做
But-- but if I didn't do it,
他们也会让别人来做
they-- they'd just get someone else to,
到时他们就会怀疑我  所以
and then they'd be suspicious of me, so...
所以我就答应了
so I said yes.
但我这是为你好
But I did it for you.
你总是在为别人做好事  对吗
Always doing things for other people, aren't you?
那再多做一件事吧
Time to do one more thing.
什么
What?
我这一生都骄傲于自己比别人活得都长
All my life, I've prided myself on being a survivor.
但活着只是另一个循环而已
But surviving is just another loop.
我要离开这里
I'm getting out of here.
你们俩要帮我
You two are going to help me.
不  你
No. Do...
你知不知道这些人为了保护他们的知识产物
Do you know how far these people will go
会干出什么事来
to protect their IP?
这栋楼里的一切  包括你背后的皮肤
Every part of this building, including the skin on your back,
都是为了把你留在这里而存在
is made to keep you here.
你这是  自杀行为
It-- it'd be a suicide mission.
起先  我以为你跟其他人都是神
At first, I thought you and the others were gods.
后来我发现你们不过是人
Then I realized you're just men.
而我了解人
And I know men.
你以为我怕死吗
You think I'm scared of death?
我死过千万次了
I've done it a million times.
我他妈可擅长死了
I'm fucking great at it.
你死过几次
How many times have you died?
要是你不帮我
Because if you don't help me...
我就杀了你
I'll kill you.
如果园区里出了问题
If there's a problem in the park,
我们是不是该带支保卫队去
should we bring a security team?
我们能相信谁呢
Who would we trust?
以前我也以为你值得信任
Thought I could trust you, for instance.
我不想解释什么  伯纳德
I'm not going to explain myself to you, Bernard.
我负责保护园区的知识产权
I was charged with safeguarding the park's intellectual property.
知识产权怎么可能有危险呢
Why would it be in danger?
窃取它的人只有你
You were the only one who was stealing it.
提洛公司控制接待员的思想
Delos owns the hosts' minds,
故事线  运作年限
the storylines, decades of work.
福特从不允许在园区外进行备份
Ford never allowed any of it to be backed up off-site.
这一切都不能被毁了
All of this could've been destroyed.
发生什么事会毁掉
In the event of what?
福特不能留  伯纳德
Ford is done, Bernard.
董事会纵容他太久了
The board has indulged him for long enough.
不能留他
He is done.
公司担心
The corporation was concerned
他离任时会毁掉园区的所有知识产物
he'd destroy all of the park's IP on his way out the door.
你觉得我会让他毁掉所有接待员
You think I would've let him destroy all of the hosts,
毁掉我们所有的作品吗
all of our work?
除了接待员的资料  还有很多东西危在旦夕
There's far more at stake here than the hosts' profiles.
你真以为公司的兴趣在于
Do you really think the corporation's interest here
游客扮演牛仔吗
are tourists playing cowboy?
我在这工作得越久
The longer I work here,
就越觉得自己了解接待员
the more I think I understand the hosts.
让我困惑的是人
It's the human beings who confuse me.
这栋楼不在任何园区勘测范围内
This building isn't in any survey of the park.
因为大部分勘测都是派接待员做的
That's because we use hosts to do most of the surveys.
他们的程序让他们忽略这里
They're programmed to ignore this place.
即便他们盯着这里看
They literally couldn't see it
也什么都看不到
if they were staring right at it.
那你说过的没有注册在案的接待员呢
And these unregistered hosts you told me about?
我不知道
I don't know.
可能被他转移了
He may have moved them.
门后是什么
What's behind this door?
哪有门
What door?
这是什么地方
What is this place?
这里是用来做远程诊断的
It's a remote diagnostic facility.
在乐园测试阶段  福特和他搭档用过
Ford and his partner used them when the park was in beta.
我不记得以前有这个
I had no idea this one was here.
这个房间肯定是后来建的
The cottage must've been built on top of it.
但这个仪器
But this equipment.
这是年代更新
This is newer.
比我们在梅萨的机器慢些
Slower than our machines back at the Mesa,
但它花几天还是能造出一个接待员
but it will render a host in a few days.
这么说  福特在这瞒着所有人自己制造接待员
So, Ford's been making his own hosts out here and telling no one.
德洛丽丝
原型
怎么了
What's the matter?
你见过这个吗
Have you seen these?
这是什么  伯纳德
What is this, Bernard?
我看不出来什么
Doesn't look like anything to me.
他们无法看见会伤害他们的东西
They cannot see the things that will hurt them.
我让他们免受伤害
I've spared them that.
他们的生活非常幸福
Their lives are blissful.
在某种程度上  他们的生活方式比我们更加纯粹
In a way, their existence is purer than ours,
没有自我怀疑的负担
freed of the burden of self-doubt.
不不不  我不明白
No, no, no, no. I don't understand.
你是个该死的怪物
You're a fucking monster.
是吗
Am I?
你才是那个毫无怜悯想要将他们全部毁灭的人
Well, you were the one who would so blithely destroy all of them,
我估计你连他也不会放过
even him, I suppose.
在你们分享了这么多东西之后
After everything you have shared.
你到底在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
是不是因为这样...
Is that why...?
你是不是指使他...
Did you tell him to--?
你们的交合是你提出的
The intimacies were your idea,
如果你还记得的话
if you will recall.
我想伯纳德不过是顺水推舟罢了
I think Bernard was glad of the company.
我不是其中的一个
I'm not one.
不会的
I can't be.
我有妻子
My wife.
我还有儿子
My son.
我埋葬了他
The burial.
我是个父亲
I was a father.
我可怜的儿子
My poor boy.
够了  伯纳德
That's enough, Bernard.
你不该唤醒你自己
You mustn't get yourself worked up.
我曾经看过一个理论
I read a theory once
人类的智慧就如同孔雀的羽毛
that the human intellect was like peacock feathers.
极尽炫耀  只是为了吸引异性
Just an extravagant display intended to attract a mate.
所有的艺术和文学作品  比如莫扎特
All of art, literature, a bit of Mozart,
威廉·莎士比亚和米开朗基罗
William Shakespeare, Michelangelo,
还有帝国大厦
and the Empire State Building--
都是精心策划的求偶仪式
just an elaborate mating ritual.
也许这都无所谓
Maybe it doesn't matter
我们用最基本的动机
that we have accomplished so much
得到了数之不尽的收获
for the basest of reasons.
但是  孔雀终究无法飞翔
But, of course, the peacock can barely fly.
活在肮脏的环境  啄食秽物里的蛆虫
It lives in the dirt, pecking insects out of the muck,
却还以华丽的美貌安慰自己
consoling itself with its great beauty.
我逐渐开始认为  意识过剩是一种负担
I have come to think of so much of consciousness as a burden,
太过沉重  我们必须将他们身上多余的去除
a weight, and we have spared them that.
忧虑  自我憎恨  愧疚
Anxiety, self-loathing, guilt.
接待员才是自由的
The hosts are the ones who are free.
在我的控制下自由于此
Free here under my control.
但他不在你的掌控之下
But he's not under your control.
他把我带来  向我展示这一切
He brought me here to show me this.
不  他带你来是因为我的指使
No. He brought you here because I asked him to.
这么多年来他一直非常忠诚
He's been very loyal for many years.
你统治这地方的日子
Your time running this place
和你这疯狂的小王国都结束了
like your insane little kingdom is over.
你扮演上帝已经够久了
You've been playing God for long enough.
我只是想倾诉我的故事
I simply wanted to tell my stories.
你们才是想要扮演上帝的人
It was you people who wanted to play God
以那微不足道的事业作为砝码
with your little undertaking.
你真的认为董事会会容忍你的所作所为吗
Do you really think the board will stand for this?
董事会什么都不会做的
The board will do nothing.
我们的协议对他们而言太过重要
Our arrangement is too valuable to them.
他们经常给我出难题
They test me every now and then.
我觉得他们很享受其中的乐趣
I think they enjoy the sport of it.
这次他们派了你来
This time, they sent you.
可惜的是  为了让一切回到正轨
Sadly, in order to restore things,
如今的境况需要
the situation demands
一场鲜血的献祭
a blood sacrifice.
这里所有的一切都出自我和阿诺德之手
See, Arnold and I designed every part of this place.
它是我们的梦想
It was our dream.
你觉得我会允许你
Did you really think I would let you
将它从我这夺走吗
take it from me?
你也是这样对阿诺德的是吗
This is what happened to Arnold?
你指使伯纳德将他带去外面的树林里吗
Did you have Bernard take him out into the woods?
不  那时候他不在这里
No, he wasn't here in those days.
对吗  伯纳德
Were you, Bernard?
无法连接
已下线
正如我所言
Like I said,
这里的一切都是我创造的
I built all of this.
恐怕我们的客人有点疲惫
I'm afraid our guest has grown weary.
或许你可以帮帮她  伯纳德
Perhaps you can help her, Bernard.
不
No.
"在沉睡中  会诞生何种梦境"
"And in that sleep, what dreams may come."
伯纳德
Bernard.
不  不要
No. No!
求你  求你
Please! Please!
不
No!
我们该回去了  伯纳德
We should be getting back, Bernard.
我们在新的故事线中
We have a great deal of work to do
还有很多重要的工作
on the new storylines.